<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ps811 on Michael DeCrescenzo</title>
    <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/categories/ps811/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ps811 on Michael DeCrescenzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mikedecr.github.io/categories/ps811/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3: Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Objective In this lesson, we will introduce how to do statistical analysis using R. Topics that you should cover to prepare for the take-home exercise include…
 Confidence intervals and tests of population means and proportions regression models and formatting model output post-estimation diagnosis and visualization  This page also contains some content on more advanced topics, but these won’t be necessary for the take-home exercise. These include…
 intermediate R tools and routines lists apply() functions mapping functions to nested data frames custom functions type coercion a reference list of tools for advanced analysis time series panel models multilevel models Bayesian models etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2: Graphics</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Objective The goal of this lesson is to provide an introduction to graphics in R, by way of ggplot2 in particular. We will cover:
 The “grammar of graphics”—the “gg” in ggplot How ggplot2 works Common geoms for social science data Customizing the appearance of ggplot graphic Saving graphics Some (not too much) discussion of the ways base graphics and ggplot2 are different  Some notes to get us started:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1: Data Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-data/</guid>
      <description>Schedule: Read this before our first R lecture.
 Objective The goal of this lesson is to simulate some data manipulation for a research project. This requires…
 setting up the project on your computer Get data onto the computer (the ANES should already be downloaded!) Load the data into R Cleaning and modifying the data Doing some simple calculations  Future lessons pick up where this one leaves off, so you must complete this lesson!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-basics/</guid>
      <description>Schedule: Read this before our first R lecture.
 Objectives This document describes how to get started with R and understand its basics. We discuss installing R, running simple commands, and some elementary programming concepts such as indexing, logic, and functions. We close with some higher-level discussion about the differences between R and Stata.
Note: Although I promised concrete lessons, this one unfortunately has to be a little more “abstract” than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoliSci 811: R Introduction</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-intro/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the online lessons for PS 811: Introduction to Statistical Computing for Political Science. This series of blog posts contain instructional notes for using R for political science research.
This current post contains a few introductory remarks about R, how I intend to teach R, and the structure of our coming lessons.
Schedule: Read this before our first R lecture.
 A little about R R is not the only program out there for doing statistical programming, so let’s begin by talking about what makes it unique.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>