<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methods on Michael DeCrescenzo</title>
    <link>/tags/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methods on Michael DeCrescenzo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Michael DeCrescenzo {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Primaries Work? Local Partisan Preferences in Nominating Elections
</title>
      <link>/research/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page under construction!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS 270: Understanding Political Numbers
</title>
      <link>/teaching/numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/numbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data are increasingly prevalent in politics (and in journalism, industry, academia&amp;hellip;), but data are complex and challenging. What can we learn about politics, and the social world more broadly, when we take an empirical view of it? When should we trust data, and when will data lead us astray?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Political science 270 is an undergraduate course on consuming, criticizing, and producing data-driven analysis of political and social phenomena. Students learn to think about political data as evidence for or against social theories. The course emphasis practical data analysis skills that apply beyond the political science curriculum, including elementary statistical analysis, R programming (&lt;code&gt;Rstudio&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;), and technical writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View course materials on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mikedecr/political-numbers-s19/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Github&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS 811: Introductory Statistical Computing for Political Science
</title>
      <link>/teaching/computing-811/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/computing-811/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2018 I co-taught a computing course for first-year political science graduate students. I covered R, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://miamioh.edu/cas/academics/departments/political-science/about/faculty-staff/faculty-bios/chapman/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hannah Chapman&lt;/a&gt; covered Stata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My instructional notes for the class are all online &lt;a href=&#34;/courses/811&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Source code (&lt;code&gt;.rmd&lt;/code&gt; files) for these workbooks are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mikedecr/site-leavit/tree/master/content/811&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partisanship, Mobilization, and Persuasion in Group Voting: A Study of the Gender Gap
</title>
      <link>/research/gender-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/gender-gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/gap-flow.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groups in the electorate vote differently from one another. Racial minorities and young voters prefer Democratic candidates on average, while evangelicals and rural voters prefer Republican candidates. How do these group differences affect party vote shares, given that the underlying groups are differently sized? We provide a theoretical framework to understand group differences in voting and party vote by expressing each as the result of partisan predispositions in the electorate that are transformed through partisan mobilization, partisan defection, and the choices of unaffiliated voters. We apply this method to the gender gap in U.S. presidential voting. We find that the size of the gender gap has no necessary bearing on the partisan vote outcome. Rather, the relationship is contingent on the changing numerical impact of partisanship, partisan mobilization, and persuasion over time. Although the gender gap and the Democratic vote in presidential elections have both increased over the years, this relationship is spurious. The primary cause of the gender gap (partisan change) was actually harmful to the Democrats. Meanwhile, forces that increased the Democratic vote (mobilization and persuasion) were minor influences on the gender gap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Causal Inference in Political Science
</title>
      <link>/research/causal-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/causal-bayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/reeves-pooling.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Causal inference and Bayesian analysis are two powerful and attractive methodological approaches for conducting empirical research, but rarely in political science does a single study employ both approaches. This stands in contrast to other fields&amp;mdash;such as psychology, epidemiology, and biostatistics&amp;mdash;where Bayesian and causal methods are more commonly applied together. In this paper I argue that the partition between these methodological schools in political science has no inherent basis in their fundamental goals, which are actually quite compatible: generating the best parameter estimates. In fact, Bayesian analysis provides a number of distinct benefits for estimating statistical models for causal inference. The methodological partition instead owes itself to informal norms surrounding each school in empirical political science. I discuss these sources of normative tension, describe go-to practices doing Bayesian inference for a skeptical audience, and demonstrate these practices using real examples from recent political science publications. The purpose of the paper is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to convince all causal inference practitioners to adopt Bayesian estimation. The purpose is to show that Bayesian methods deserve space in the study of causal effects because they improve causal estimates and provide an appealing framework for evaluating causal evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unexceptional Gender Gap of 2016
</title>
      <link>/research/gender-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/gender-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/gap-16.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the particular candidates who ran, the 2016 presidential campaign was defined by gender to a remarkable degree. This led many observers to expect a historically large gender gap in voting. In contrast to these expectations, the gender gap between men and women’s votes in 2016 was only slightly larger than in other recent elections. We argue that an immense gender divide did not emerge because it was constrained by high levels of partisanship in the electorate, especially “negative partisanship” toward the opposing party that leaves little room for gender to matter. In addition, we challenge two common assumptions: that the gender gap helps Democratic candidates and that women were more persuadable than men over the course of the campaign. Both men and women vacillated in their views of Clinton’s honesty during the campaign, with men shifting away from her and toward Trump just before election day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cite-this-paper&#34;&gt;Cite this paper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burden, Barry C., Evan Crawford, and Michael G. DeCrescenzo. 2016. &amp;ldquo;The Unexceptional Gender Gap of 2016.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;The Forum&lt;/em&gt; 14(4), 415–432.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-tex&#34;&gt;@article{burden-crawford-decrescenzo:2016:gender-gap,
  title = {The Unexceptional Gender Gap of 2016},
  author = {Burden, Barry C and Crawford, Evan and DeCrescenzo, Michael G},
  journal = {The Forum},
  volume = {14},
  number = {4},
  pages = {415--432},
  year = {2016},
  publisher = {De Gruyter}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
