<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Michael DeCrescenzo</title>
    <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Michael DeCrescenzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mikedecr.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day &#34;0&#34;: R Basics</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-basics/</guid>
      <description>What is on this web page Please guide yourself through this web page before our first in-class R lesson. It would be best if you walked through this document in enough advance of class that you can ask me questions about any confusing parts in enough advance of class. I just want to use our class time as effectively as possible!
This document describes how to get started with R and do some basic (but often useful) tricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoliSci 811: R Introduction</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/811/811-intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Materials for this course are written for graduate students in political science at the University of Wisconsin–Madison. Individuals from wider audiences may find some material here useful, but they should be aware that they are not the intended audience.
 R: the Why As a researcher, you should always be doing automated analysis. That is, your analysis should be controlled by code, rather than spread sheet formulas or drop-down menus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://mikedecr.github.io/post/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikedecr.github.io/post/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>