<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elections on Michael DeCrescenzo</title>
    <link>/tags/elections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elections on Michael DeCrescenzo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Michael DeCrescenzo {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Primaries Work? Bayesian Causal Models of Partisan Ideology and Congressional Nominations
</title>
      <link>/research/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As partisanship increasingly drives general election competition in the U.S., party nomination contests seem increasingly important in determining who represents a district in Congress.
At the same time, many ideas about how primaries affect representation in the U.S. are not supported by empirical research.
Do primary elections faithfully represent the policy preferences of local partisan voters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientists believe that candidates for office face a trade-off in the way they position themselves ideologically.
To win the nomination, candidate must champion their party&amp;rsquo;s values, but winning the general election requires the support of a broader cross-section of the electorate.
Political scientists have called termed this the &amp;ldquo;strategic positioning dilemma&amp;rdquo;—the candidate must be partisan enough to win the nomination, but not so partisan that they lose the general election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theory of primaries rests on shaky ground both theoretically and empirically.
Theoretically, primary elections present voters with high informational demands.
Learning the policy positions of different candidates is costly, especially when all candidates share the same party label.
Moreover, a candidate&amp;rsquo;s support among informal networks of party-aligned interest groups may be more important to their nominations than their ideological &amp;ldquo;fit&amp;rdquo; with partisan voters in the district.
Empirically, research of representation in primaries is held back by a limited understanding of local partisans&amp;rsquo; policy preferences.
Most existing research measures voters&amp;rsquo; preferences using coarse proxies that do not distinguish between Republican and Democratic groups or may not meaningfully capture policy preferences at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dissertation seeks to improve the measurement of the policy preferences of partisan voters at the local level and apply these new measures to the study of representation in primary elections.
Along the way, it exposes and clarifies key causal assumptions at work in prior research, and it explores new methodological tools for the statistical analysis of a broader range of causal inference problems in political science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;non-id.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals-of-this-project&#34;&gt;Goals of this project:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create novel estimates for the policy ideology (ideal points) of partisan groups within Congressional districts—435 districts x 2 parties = 870 groups—using custom Bayesian IRT modeling approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply novel estimates of local partisan preferences to test key theoretical claims about representation in primary elections: does the extremism/moderation of local ideology (&lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;) meaningfully affect the extremism/moderation of primary candidates for Congress (&lt;em&gt;Y1&lt;/em&gt;) and the extremism/moderation of the candidate eventually selected to run in the general election (&lt;em&gt;Y2&lt;/em&gt;)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore a Bayesian framework for causal inference in political science: formal notation, theoretical clarity on the meaning and application of priors, and practical guidance for pragmatic causal inference with Bayesian value-added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extend Bayesian framework to computational causal inference approaches using machine learning methods, with a focus on structural causal models (DAGs) and neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voter Identification and Nonvoting in Wisconsin—Evidence from the 2016 Election</title>
      <link>/publication/nonvoters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nonvoters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/nonvoting-posteriors.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partisanship, Mobilization, and Persuasion in Group Voting: A Study of the Gender Gap
</title>
      <link>/research/gender-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/gender-gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Groups in the electorate vote differently from one another.
Racial minorities and young voters prefer Democratic candidates on average, while evangelicals and rural voters prefer Republican candidates.
How do these group differences affect party vote shares, given that the underlying groups are differently sized?
Most research characterizes voting preferences by conditioning vote choices on group membership, which obscures the numerical impact of group dynamics in voting across time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We lay out a theoretical framework and a generative modeling approach to understand how group differences in voting evolve over time and aggregate into election outcomes.
The approach decomposes group shares into useful theoretical components for understanding how groups affect elections and in what way: partisan predispositions, partisan mobilization, swing voting, and the choices of party-unaffiliated voters.
The method traces how these theoretical mechanisms change over time, and it can be extended for multichotomous groups and more complex hierarchical modeling approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We apply this new method to the gender gap in U.S. presidential voting.
Many observers speculate that a larger gender gap in voting—larger Democratic vote shares among women than among men—numerically benefits the Democratic Party.
We show, by contrast, that the size of the gender gap has no necessary bearing on the partisan vote outcome.
Rather, the relationship is contingent on the changing numerical impact of partisanship, partisan mobilization, and persuasion over time.
Although the gender gap and the Democratic vote in presidential elections have both increased over the years, this relationship is spurious.
The primary cause of the gender gap (partisan change) was actually harmful to the Democrats.
Meanwhile, forces that increased the Democratic vote (mobilization and persuasion) were minor influences on the gender gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insights enabled by this approach can be extended to other salient groups in the electorate including race, urban/rural divisions, socioeconomic groups, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/gap-flow.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/gaps-time.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Causal Inference in Political Science
</title>
      <link>/research/causal-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/causal-bayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Causal inference and Bayesian analysis are two powerful and attractive methodological approaches for conducting empirical research, but rarely in political science does a single study employ both approaches.
This stands in contrast to other fields&amp;mdash;such as psychology, epidemiology, and biostatistics&amp;mdash;where Bayesian and causal methods are more commonly applied together.
In this paper I argue that the partition between these methodological schools in political science has no inherent basis in their fundamental goals, which are actually quite compatible.
In fact, Bayesian analysis provides a number of distinct benefits for estimating statistical models for causal inference.
The methodological partition instead owes itself to informal norms surrounding each school in empirical political science.
I discuss these sources of normative tension, describe go-to practices doing skeptical Bayesian causal inference, and demonstrate these practices using real examples from recent political science publications.
The purpose of the paper is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to convince all causal inference practitioners to adopt Bayesian estimation.
The purpose is to show how Bayesian methods add value to causal effects by improving causal estimates and providing an appealing framework for evaluating causal evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/hall-flat.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/reeves-pooling.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polls, Forecasts, and Voters’ Perceptions of Uncertainty
</title>
      <link>/research/forecast-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/forecast-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper uses a conjoint experiment to study how common journalistic practices for presenting polling data affect audience confidence in election outcomes.
Using a survey experiment of Mechanical Turk (MTurk) participants, we study how people process polling data when it is expressed as a single poll, as an average of recent polls, or as a probabilistic forecast.
The conjoint study varies the circumstances of the election—vote share for each candidate, the amount of undecided voters—and journalistic strategies believed to improve the audience&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of uncertain polling information—language about margins of sampling error and graphical depictions of uncertainty and possible election outcomes.
Our results help to empirically ground discussions about ways to improve coverage of survey data and public opinion by accounting for how the public actually understands and makes sense polls and forecasts, aligning journalistic aims with strategies for effective communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unexceptional Gender Gap of 2016
</title>
      <link>/publication/gender-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/gender-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/research/gap-16.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
