<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Michael DeCrescenzo</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Michael DeCrescenzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Hugo themes (that I did not pick)</title>
      <link>/2018/2018-09-23-hugo-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/2018-09-23-hugo-themes/</guid>
      <description>I just finished a major website overhaul. While it took only about one day of work, I’ve had my eyes open for a new theme for Hugo for a while.
I mean, a while. I would download a theme, give it a 15-minute test run offline, and decide that it wasn’t for me. I did that maybe a dozen times.1
But this is mainly my fault. I am a bad combination of picky and unskilled with websites and web design, which made me a fickle chooser throughout the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packages &amp; Reproducibility: Install what you need, attach what you want</title>
      <link>/2018/2018-05-26-reproducible-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/2018-05-26-reproducible-packages/</guid>
      <description>(Note: An earlier version of this post referred to “loading” packages when I really meant “attaching.” Thanks to Thomas Leeper for the clarification.)
When we distribute R code (for publication/replication archives, on Github, through blog posts, etc), we like the code to run smoothly on someone else’s machine. Packages present a nominal problem because different users have different packages installed on their computer. Ideally the script we are distributing should install dependencies without the redundancy of re-installing packages that a user already has installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3: Analysis</title>
      <link>/811/811-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/811/811-analysis/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(cache = TRUE) Schedule Read this before our final lecture, after the graphics lesson.
 How to follow along A script file walking through some of these commands is available here.
 Objectives In this lesson, we will introduce how to do statistical analysis using R. Topics that you should cover to prepare for the take-home exercise include…
 Means, confidence intervals, and simple significance tests Estimating regression models Generating model output Model diagnostics and fit statistics Post-estimation graphics (model predictions)  This page also contains some content on more advanced topics, but these won’t be necessary for the take-home exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2: Graphics</title>
      <link>/811/811-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/811/811-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Schedule: Read this before our second R lecture, after the data lesson.
 How to follow along A script file walking through some of these commands is available here.
 Objectives The goal of this lesson is to provide an introduction to graphics in R, by way of ggplot2 in particular. We will cover:
 The “grammar of graphics”—the “gg” in ggplot How ggplot2 works Common graphics in social science Customizing the appearance of ggplot graphic Saving graphics  Some notes to get us started:  This lesson makes liberal use of pipe chains, which bundle many operations together in one block of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1: Data Manipulation</title>
      <link>/811/811-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/811/811-data/</guid>
      <description>Overview Schedule: Read this before our first R lecture.
 How to follow along A script file walking through some of these commands is available here.
 Objectives The goal of this lesson is to simulate some data manipulation for a research project. This requires…
 setting up the project on your computer Get data onto the computer (the ANES should already be downloaded!) Load the data into R Cleaning and modifying the data Doing some simple calculations  Future lessons pick up where this one leaves off, so you must complete this lesson!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R</title>
      <link>/811/811-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/811/811-basics/</guid>
      <description>Schedule: Read this before our first R lecture.
 How to follow along Follow the instructions in this lesson in your own .R script.
 Objectives This document describes how to get started with R and understand its basics. We discuss installing R, running simple commands, and some elementary programming concepts such as indexing, logic, and functions. We close with some higher-level discussion about the differences between R and Stata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoliSci 811: R Introduction</title>
      <link>/811/811-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/811/811-intro/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the online lessons for PS 811: Introduction to Statistical Computing for Political Science. This series of blog posts contain instructional notes for using R for political science research.
This current post contains a few introductory remarks about R, how I intend to teach R, and the structure of our coming lessons.
Schedule: Read this before our first in-class R lesson!
 A little about R R is not the only program out there for doing statistical programming, so let’s begin by talking about what makes it unique.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>